[Applause]
[掌声]
turn
转动
we are living in a historical moment marked by a difficult style we know
我们生活在一个历史性的时刻，我们以一种艰难的风格为标志
the world is shaken by the crisis caused by the pandemic of the expert name that
专家名称的大流行引起的危机动摇了世界
highlights even more another global challenge the socio crisis
凸显了社会危机的又一全球挑战
environmental this places us all in front of the
环境这使我们所有人都走在了前面
need for a choice the choice between what matters and what doesn't
需要做出选择，在重要和不重要之间进行选择
the choice between continuing to ignore the sufferings of the poorest and to
在继续忽略最贫穷者的痛苦与继续
mistreat our common home the earth or commit ourselves at every level
虐待地球上的共同家园或在各个层面上献身
to transform the way we act science tells us every day with more
改变我们的行为方式科学每天都在告诉我们更多
precision that it is necessary to act urgently and I am not exaggerating this says it
这是必须采取紧急行动的精确度，我对此并不夸大
science if we are to have a hope of avoiding climate change
科学，如果我们希望避免气候变化
among which and catastrophic and for this to act knowledge this is a given
其中，灾难性的，要让它采取行动，这是给定的
scientific know the conscience tells us that we can not be
科学知道良心告诉我们，我们不能
indifferent to the suffering of the poorest to the growing ones
对最贫穷的人对成长中的人的痛苦漠不关心
economic inequalities and social injustices and the economy itself
经济不平等，社会不公与经济本身
can not be limited to production and distribution must consider
不能仅限于生产和分销必须考虑
necessarily its impact on the environment and the dignity of the person
必然对环境和人的尊严产生影响
we could say that the economy must be creative
我们可以说，经济必须具有创造力
it in its methods in the way of acting creativity limit yourself to undertake
它以行动方式发挥创造力的方式限制了您自己承担的责任
together a journey a journey of transformation and action not done
在一起的旅程没有完成变革和行动的旅程
so much of words but above all of concrete and urgent actions
太多的话，但最重要的是具体而紧急的行动
we think about travel because it requires a shift, a change from it
我们之所以考虑旅行，是因为它需要转变，也需要转变
crisis none of us must come out the same not
危机我们所有人都不能一样出来
it can come out the same from a crisis, never comes out the same and it will take time and effort
它可以从危机中脱颖而出，永远不会脱颖而出，这需要时间和精力
to get out of it it will be necessary to go step by step to help the weak persuade i
为了摆脱困境，有必要一步一步地帮助弱者说服
doubters imagine new solutions and commit to carry them forward but
怀疑者想像出新的解决方案，并承诺将其推进，但是
the goal is clear to build over the next decade
未来十年的目标很明确
a world where the needs of the present generations can be met
一个可以满足当代人需求的世界
including everyone without compromising the possibilities of future generations
包括每个人而又不损害子孙后代的可能性
I would like to invite all people of Christian faith or not
我想邀请所有信奉基督教的人
and all people of good will to embark on this journey from his
所有有善意的人都会从他的身边出发
faith or if he does not have faith from his will in his own good will
信仰，或者如果他对自己的善意没有信心
each each of us as individuals and members of family groups
我们每个人都是个人和家庭成员
faith communities enterprises associations institutions and can make a contribution
信仰社区企业协会机构，可以做出贡献
significant
重大
five years ago I wrote the encyclical letter laudato be dedicated to care
五年前，我写了一封通俗的信laudato致力于护理
of our common home proposes the concept of integral ecology for
我们共同的家提出了整体生态学的概念
respond together to the cry of the earth but also to the cry of the poor
共同回应大地的哀号，也回应穷人的哀号
integral ecology and an invitation to an integral vision of life to leave
完整的生态学和对离开生活的完整愿景的邀请
from the belief that everything in the world is connected and that as the
相信世界上的所有事物都是相互联系的，
pandemic we are interdependent on each other
大流行，我们相互依存
others and even dependent on our mother earth from such a vision
其他人甚至从这样的视角依赖我们的母亲
the need to seek other ways of understanding progress and measuring it
需要寻求其他方式来了解进度并对其进行衡量
without limiting ourselves to the economic technological and financial dimension of al
而不局限于自己的经济技术和财务层面
gross product but giving a central importance to the social dimensions and type
总产值，但对社会规模和类型至关重要
and educational activities, today I would like to propose three courses of action
和教育活动，今天我想提出三项行动方案
as written in laudato be the change and the right orientation for
如laudato所写，是改变和正确的方向
the journey of ecology and integral requires you to take a step first
生态与整体的旅程要求您先迈出一步
educational type
教育类型
therefore the first proposal is to promote at every level
因此，第一个建议是在各个层面上进行推广
an education in the care of the common home by developing an understanding that i
通过发展对以下方面的理解，对公共家园进行教育：
environmental problems are related to human needs we must understand
环境问题与人类需求有关，我们必须了解
this from the beginning environmental problems are linked to human needs
从一开始就将环境问题与人类需求联系在一起
an education based on scientific data and an ethical approach
基于科学数据和道德方法的教育
I am heartened by the fact that many young people already have this important
许多年轻人已经拥有了这个重要的事实，这让我感到鼓舞
a new ecological and social sensitivity and some of them are fighting in such a way
一种新的生态和社会敏感性，其中一些以这种方式挣扎
generous for the defense of the environment and for justice as a second proposal
慷慨地捍卫环境和正义是第二项建议
more emphasis needs to be placed on water and nutrition access to water
需要更加重视水和获取水的营养
safe drinking and a universal and essential human and social right
安全饮酒和普遍的基本人权和社会权利
because it determines the survival of people and therefore the conditions for
因为它决定了人的生存，因此决定了人们的生存条件
the exercise of any other right and responsibility to ensure
行使任何其他权利和责任以确保
adequate nutrition for all through non farming methods
通过非农耕方式为所有人提供充足的营养
destructive should then become the fundamental purpose of the entire cycle of
然后，破坏性应成为整个生命周期的基本目标。
production and distribution of food the third proposal is that of
食品的生产和分配的第三项建议是
energy transition a gradual but immediate replacement of
能源过渡逐步但立即替代
fossil fuels with clean energy sources
具有清洁能源的化石燃料
we have a few years the scientists calculate to proceed
我们有几年的科学家打算继续
approximately less than 30 we have a few years less than 30
大约少于30我们有几年少于30
to drastically reduce greenhouse gas emissions into the atmosphere
大大减少向大气排放的温室气体
this transition must be not only rapid and able to satisfy needs
这种转变不仅必须迅速而且能够满足需求
of present and future energy but also must be attentive to the impacts on
现在和未来的能源，但也必须注意对能源的影响
poor on local populations and on those who work in the production sectors
在当地人口和生产部门工作的人中穷人
of energy a way to encourage this change
能量是促进这种变化的一种方式
and to lead businesses towards the urgent need for
并引导企业迫切需要
commit to the integral care of the common home by excluding from
通过排除以下因素来致力于共同家园的整体照顾
investments companies that do not meet i
不符合我的投资公司
integral vestments of ecology and rewarding those who work
生态学不可或缺的部分，并奖励那些工作的人
concretely in this transition phase to place at the center of
具体地，在此过渡阶段中，将其放置在
their activities parameters such as sustainability, social justice and
他们的活动参数，例如可持续性，社会公正和
promotion of the common good many Catholic and other organizations
促进许多天主教徒和其他组织的共同利益
other faiths have already taken on the responsibility of working in this
其他信仰已经承担了在此工作的责任
direction in fact the land must be worked and cared for, cultivated and protected
实际上，必须对土地进行耕作，照料，耕种和保护
we can't keep squeezing like an orange and we can say this
我们不能一直像橘子一样挤，我们可以这样说
looking after the land is a human right
照顾土地是一项人权
these three proposals go intense as part of a large set of actions that
这三项提案作为大量行动的一部分而变得激烈起来，
we must carry on in an integrated way to arrive at a solution
我们必须以一种综合的方式进行合作以得出解决方案
lasting problems the current economic system is
当前经济体制存在的持久问题
unsustainable we are faced with the moral imperative e
不可持续，我们面临道德上的当务之急
the practical urge to rethink many things how we produce how we consume
重新思考许多事情的实际冲动我们如何生产我们如何消费
think our culture of waste the short-term vision it
认为我们的文化浪费了短期的眼光吧
exploitation of the poor indifference towards them
剥削对他们的冷漠
the increase in inequalities and the dependence on energy sources from
不平等的增加和对能源的依赖
our challenges but we must think integral ecology suggests one
我们面临的挑战，但我们必须认为整体生态学表明
new concession of the relationship between us with nature this brings a new one
我们与自然之间关系的新让步带来了新的
economy in which the production of wealth is directed towards well-being
以财富生产为福祉的经济
integral of the human being and the improvement not the destruction of
人的整体性和改善而不是破坏
our common home also means a renewed policy conceived as one
我们共同的家园也意味着一种新的政策
of the highest forms of charity yes interpersonal love but also
最高形式的慈善是人际交往的爱，但也
love and politics envelops all peoples involves nature
爱情和政治笼罩着所有民族与自然的融合
I therefore invite everyone and everyone to undertake this trip I recommend
因此，我建议所有人，每个人都进行这次旅行，我建议
proposed in the laudato Sì and also in the new encyclical Brothers All Like
在laudatoSì和新的百科全书《 Brothers All Like》中提出
suggests the term amnesty we must urgently act each of
建议大赦一词，我们必须紧急采取行动，
we can play a valuable role if we all get on the road
如果我们都上路，我们可以发挥重要作用
today not tomorrow today
今天今天不是明天
because the future is built today and not built alone but in community
因为未来是今天建立的，不是一个人建立的，而是在社区中建立的
and in harmony thanks [Music]
和声谢谢[音乐]